Death Rises From Deep Below
Mongolian Death Worm is a horror, science fiction, tv
movie film directed by Steven R. Monroe.
When an American oil company sets up an experimental drilling plant out
in the vast deserts of Mongolia, they awaken a nest.
The deadly creatures begin to breed and spread,
devouring everyone in their path.
The only person who can stop them is treasure hunter and adventure seeker who spent his life
searching for a legendary tomb, fabled to be protected by the Death Worms.
He knows he must do what he can to kill the creatures, but stopping
these monsters may mean destroying his life's work forever!
Daniel, played by Sean Patrick Flanery.
Alicia, played by Victoria Pratt.
Timur, played by George Cheung.
Patrick, played by Drew Waters.
Mr. Bixler, played by Matthew Tompkins.
Phillip, played by Nate Rubin.
The Mongolian death worm (Mongolian: олгой-хорхой, olgoi-khorkhoi, "large
intestine-worm") is a creature alleged to exist in the Gobi Desert.
Investigations into the legendary creature have been pursued by amateur cryptozoologists and
credentialed academics alike, but little evidence has been found to support its existence.
It can be considered a cryptid or a mythological animal.
Tales of the creature first came to Western attention as a result of Roy
Chapman Andrews's 1926 book On the Trail of Ancient Man.
The American paleontologist described second-hand tales of the monster that he heard at a gathering of Mongolian officials: "None of those present ever had seen the creature, but they all firmly believed in its
existence and described it minutely."
In 1983, a specimen of Tartar sand boa (Eryx tataricus) was shown to locals who claimed to have seen "olgoi-khorkhoi" and they confirmed that this was the same animal.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.